## STEPHEN BLANEY

Bachelor of Science, BSc (Hons), Computing

**?** 7 Brian Avenue, Marino , Dublin 3

**\** 085 234 4100

☑blaney.stephen9@gmail.com

in linkedin.com/in/stephen-blaney-288a55117/

github.com/StephenBlaney

# FINAL YEAR PROJECT

As my final year project i worked on a Android A.I application that was specifically tailored towards visually disabled individuals using IBM Watson Technology. This program would allow the client to use voice command to access the various features of the device e.g. phone Dialer, contacts, time, battery, alarm, calendar etc. enhancing the user experience. The project also has specific features added in to the project that would prove useful such as an Optical Character Reader that would allow the user to read printed text and money that would be returned as speech by the A.I

The project involves the following technology's . **IBM Watson**, **Java**, **GitHub**, **Google Vision**, **Android Studio** and **XML** 

## TECHNOLOGY SUMMARY

Android, XML, RapidMiner, Java, Python, C#, Angular, PHP, Symphony , HTML, CSS, JSON, R, SQL, Github, JavaScript, Unity, typescript, IBM Watson, Google Vision, C, Ajax, Firebase, Windows, Linux, Word, Excel, Tensor Flow

#### SUMMARY

Recently graduated from college at the institute of technology Blanchardstown (ITB) with a first class honors computer science degree , and currently looking for employment within my field. I studied computing full time on a 4 year course with the hopes of working in the software development/Big Data industry. I'm very outgoing and love meeting new people with different experiences. Keen to expand skills and knowledge and prepared to work in a variety of roles. My main career focus are in Machine learning and Big Data Analytics. Currently working as a document controller for Designer Group

### **EDUCATION**

2008 - 2014 Leaving Certificate

Colaiste Mhurie, Ballygar, Galway

2014 - 2018 Computer Science Bachelor's Degree (Hons), First Class Honours,

GPA 3.44

Institute of Technology Blanchardstown

Major Project **B** + Computational Intelligence **A** +

Text Analysis **B+** Research Skills **A+** 

Data Analytics A+ Derivation of Algorithms B+
Network Security B+ Ubiquitous Computing C

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

2018 - Present Document Controller

Designer Group

- Skilled in assisting project managers in developing and maintaining documents including drawings, and specifications.
- Proven record of effectively and efficiently maintaining site documentation storage area as per the requirements of each project
- Demonstrated ability to ensure the timely distribution and display of all documents
- Deeply familiar with receiving and processing requests for information and ensuring that they are serviced after due diligence
- Qualified to process documents for revision and approvals, along with creating and reviewing documentation according to standardized procedures.
- Unmatched ability to store, manage and track company documents by creating and implementing core document control systems.
- Proficient at using Viewpoint, Bluebeam and Field viewtechnology's

2016 - 2018 Bartender

Compass Group

- •Experience in working in extreme stressful situations with an aptitude to solve customer problems and complains.
- •Proven ability to assess, anticipate and meet multiple guests' needs simultaneously while maintaining high standards of quality.
- Special talent for adapting to different personalities of guests and coworkers without losing attention.

## **COURSE WORKS**

Advanced Programming
Computer Architecture
Information Technology Maths
Game Development
Database Fundamentals
Web Development Server-Side
Software Engineering & Testing
IT Business Management
Data Structures & Algorithms
Parallel Computing
Network Distributed Computing
Object Orientated and Design
Patterns

Web Framework Development
Data Analytics
Text Mining
Applied Human Language
Technology
Android Development
Computational Intelligence
Network Security
Advanced Network Technologies

#### **ACHIEVEMENTS**

#### **Peer Mentor**

Participated as a mentor with the ITB Mentoring Programme 2016-17 demonstrating the following

- Outstanding Leadership Skills
- Excellent Communication Skills
- Strong Teamwork Skills
- Ability and willingness to communicate what you know.
- •Good Organization Skills
- •Approachability, availability, and the ability to listen
- Objectivity and fairness

#### **Class Representative**

During my third year in collage i was successfully elected as class representative due to my open nature . My tasks where as follows.

- •Ensure that students' views on academic matters are heard
- •Feed issues back directly into their departments and courses
- •Get involved in student union campaigns
- •Attending class rep meetings to propose new ideas and raise issues

- Recognized for demonstrating teamwork, sincerity, and courtesy.
- •Developed own experience and knowledge base.
- Special talent for adapting to different personalities of guests and coworkers without losing attention.
- Ability to ensure that bar is adequately stocked.
- Checking identification of customers to verify age requirements.
- Experience with cash handling and registers

#### **SKILLS**



Interpersonal

As a result form working as class rep and mentoring my skills have improved considerably. I have no problem speaking in front large crowd of people.



Team work and Time Management

As part of the course it was vital to work as part of a team for multiple projects as a way of preparing us for the workplace. It was important to manage time effectively especially towards the end of my degree where i managed to effectively to write my thesis and study for final year exams.



Programming

Over the course of my degree there where several languages that i was proficient at including Java, Python, C# , HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Android and SQL.



Language and Writing

Fluent in English and Moderate in both Irish and French.



Organisational

As part of my position as a Document Controller it was imperative to have great organisational skills as CAD drawings must be easily accessibly when they where requested from the Engineer. This was not only for drawings but any request for information

#### **HOBBIES**

**Marathon Runner:** Have participated in various events and was even a member of the collages athletics team.

**Puzzle Solving:** Great Interest in all sorts of puzzle and problem solving games such as Sudoku, Crosswords and Riddles.

**Game Developer:** In my free time i like to my own 3D and 2D video games using the unity engine

### REFERENCES

Derek McConnell

People Operations Manager

Phone + 353 1 232 0863

Email recruitment@avivastadiumevents.ie

Aviva Stadium

Ballsbridge

Dublin 4

Fiona Ebbs

HR Administrator

Phone +353 (01) 882 1639

Email fionaebbs@designergrp.com

Clyde House

IDA Blanchardstown Business Park

Snugborough Road

Dublin 15